MAITRI SHAH

DESIGN LEADER

SKILLS

Creative Direction Design Systems Product Design Interaction Design Aaile Accessibility Project Management People Management CX Strategy Adobe CC Wireframing HTML/CSS/JS Workshops **UX** Research

CERTIFICATIONS

UX Strategy for Emerging Technologies New York University 2020

Product Management General Assembly 2018

Sharepoint 2016 Power End User **ONLC Training Center**

Web Development Immersive General Assembly 2015

PROFILE

Maitri is a design leader who is passionate about people, product and process. She is a design professional with 15 years of experience in design spanning product, UX, UI, CX and design systems for diverse organizations. She get excited about creating elegant, simple and useful solutions and continually learning and applying her skills to help solve challenges.

EDUCATION

Information Technology, Digital Media and Instructional Design

MS

Harvard University, 2013, Partially Completed

Finance

BS

Michigan State University, 2003-2007

Apparel & Textile Design

Michigan State University, 2003-2007

Fashion Design

AAS

Fashion Institute of Technology, 2005-2006

ACADEMIC ACCOMPLISHMENTS

FIT Critic's Award for Sportswear Design

MSU Independent Study resulting in addition of accredited knitwear course offering to university curriculum

MSU Broad Business College tutor for MSC 317, Quantitative **Business Research Methods**

MSU Full Merit Scholarship for 8 semesters

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE IS ON THE NEXT PAGE -





PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Arthur J. Gallagher, Chicago, IL

- Global Design Systems, Senior Manager (Jul 2021-current)

Manager of design team

Create and manage design systems for multiple brands in the Gallagher portfolio Product design - B2B and B2C SaaS

Fuego UX, Remote

- UX Design Manager (Jan 2022-current)

Manager of multiple client engagements Lead collaborative projects from concept to implementation Mentor and trains team of UX designers

Outfront Media, New York, NY

Interactive Design Lead/Manager (Jul 2019-Jul 2021)

Manager of design team

From concept to implementation, led design on multiple platforms including VR - preview tool for advertising partners

Created CX strategy for business development - helped win multiple multimillion-dollar contracts

Redesigned internal site search experience to help users more easily locate specific user-generated content

Havas North America, New York, NY

- Design Consultant (Jun 2019-Jul 2019)

Led design and copywriting team in creating a digital storytelling experience for Havas North America and creative guidelines for global distribution

Stakeholders included CEO of Havas North America, CEO of Havas New York, CMO of Havas New York

Practising Law Institute, New York, NY

- Senior Web/UI Designer (Jan 2019 - Feb 2019)

Trained and developed a team of designers

- Web/UI Designer, Practising Law Institute (Jul 2018 - Jan 2019)

Partnered with UX, product management and engineering teams on customer-facing digital product Collaborated with UX to document and maintain component library

- Web Designer, Practising Law Institute (Nov 2015 -Jul 2018)

Created promotional artwork for multichannel campaigns

Voluntarily concepted and implemented requesting system and process to improve collaboration between marketing and art teams

AIQ, New York, NY

- UX/UI Designer (Jun 2013-Jul 2015)

Created branded artwork for multiple platforms including large format DOOH Created brand identity including logo design

Freelance, New York, NY

Business Owner and Designer(Aug 2007-Jun 2013)

Self-created dance practice including performance, choreography and teaching in the NY tristate area. Created designs for NIKE, Custo Barcelona and Steve & Barry's.



